this video is to welcome cohort 6 and
welcome back cohort 5 to the active
inference textbook group at the Active
inference Institute we're reading the
book from 2022 by par pulo and friston
this video is going to give an overview
of the textbook group in terms of the
asynchronous niche this Coda document
that we'll go through here and also a
bit about the weekly meetings and how
they'll be similar and different from
last time on the cover page you can
download the PDF for The Textbook and
see more information the directory gives
an overview of some of the sections of
this Koda the onboarding section has
sections like more activities at The
Institute which is a cross document
embedding of active
activities some rules and guidelines for
the textbook group some learning
practices that people have found
relevant in their time as we're coming
from many different backgrounds with a
textbook group and have a lot of
different commitments and directions
that we're going towards and more sub
pages that might be useful for you to
copy into a document of your own or
explore your own formats
for there have been four completed
cohorts so on each of those cohort 1 2 3
and four you can see more information
and link to the recordings and starting
in January 2024 we will begin with
cohort 6 and pick up from the second
half of the book with cohort
5 so the cohort 6 meeting times are
shown here and each meeting we'll have a
theme for each theme we'll focus on
basically that however always goes above
and beyond
that for cohort 5 the past video
recordings can be watched if you want to
get back up to speed and also it will be
really exciting that a lot of the
meetings will be be facilitated by Oli
and Andrew and hopefully some others too
so that'll be great looking forward to
that the meetings are on Mondays and
they alternate within a cohort between
14 and 23 UTC so if you want to join
just for example 14 UTC every week you
could do that it would alternate
chapters and you're welcome to join
whichever chapter we're discussing
there's no need to go through the
chapters in
order the section on the textbook itself
has Pages for each chapter and
detailed tables of contents and areas
for note taking in the equation section
there's renderings of the equations
screenshots and also a few fun pages to
explore using language models to analyze
the latac code and to give translation
s and related philosophy discussions for
the equation so whether you're familiar
or not with a math in the textbook it's
all good Pages like this and the
discussions that we'll have will
hopefully be fun
figures open for anyone to add tags and
annotations boxes and tables and code
also one task that would be great to
work on this year would be for some
equations we have using the active
inference ontology the natural language
reading this is going to help a lot with
understanding and translating and
relabeling and understanding in all
these different ways and some equations
have it and where it's there it's really
helpful it's not always complete though
like equation 2.6 could use it and
others too so if that is something that
anyone wants to try that would be cool
for this time through in the discourse
section that there is a primary feature
of this document which is the questions
table and you can add questions just by
directly adding a row to this table in
whichever chapter and it's really cool
to go through see all the questions and
uh mark them as interesting if you like
them and look at all of the rich
discourse that has happened through the
times so asking questions and reviewing
questions are some of the primary ways
to participate at outside of the live
meeting so always feel like you can
improve the discourse or whatever is
written in these sections math learning
group is an informal subgroup there's
people who sometimes want to pursue the
math side and also the coding side from
uh lower level or higher level
familiarity and we'll explore that and
work that out in the first
meetings projects are where people have
listed different projects that they're
possibly working on or maybe started and
looking for collaborators ideas and
insights not questions so much but just
adding points and takeaways and
meaningful things that people got from
the book
resources useful
resources information and feedback form
that's Anonymous on the textbook
group and other erata and Corrections
for the book and lastly the active
inference tables a couple of which are
the active inference ontology this is
what we commonly referred to when using
the terms from active
inference some tables of active
inference research papers and a table
with uh videos from The Institute so
overall feel free to
explore email us if you have any
questions thank you for your interest in
the textbook group and let's have a fun
set of cohorts thank you
bye